{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1998",
                "B. 2001",
                "C. 2002",
                "D. 2003"
            ],
            "question": "The Bodoland Territorial Council was established in the year",
            "answer": "D. 2003"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kokrajhar",
                "B. Baksa",
                "C. Goalpara",
                "D. Udalguri"
            ],
            "question": "Which one district is not under the BTAD council",
            "answer": "C. Goalpara"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 12th",
                "B. 13th",
                "C. 15th",
                "D. 18th"
            ],
            "question": "By population, Assam is the _______ largest state of India",
            "answer": "C. 15th"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sivasagar",
                "B. Golaghat",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Karbi Anglong"
            ],
            "question": "Nambor Wildlife Sanctuary is located in which district",
            "answer": "D. Karbi Anglong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Cachar",
                "B. Dima Hasao",
                "C. Karbi Anglong",
                "D. West Karbi Anglong"
            ],
            "question": "Hamren is the headquater of which one District",
            "answer": "D. West Karbi Anglong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chirang",
                "B. Udalguri",
                "C. Baksa",
                "D. Bongaigaon"
            ],
            "question": "Which one district is not under Bodoland Territorial Council",
            "answer": "D. Bongaigaon"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sananta Tanty",
                "B. Jayanta Madhab Bora",
                "C. Jnan Pujari",
                "D. Arupa Kalita Patangia"
            ],
            "question": "Who wins the Sahitya Akademi Award in the year 2018",
            "answer": "A. Sananta Tanty"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Arun Sarma",
                "B. Sneha Devi",
                "C. Nirupama Borgohain",
                "D. Chandra Prasad Saikia"
            ],
            "question": "The novel \"Abhijatri\" was written by which Author",
            "answer": "C. Nirupama Borgohain"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhubanmohan Baruah",
                "B. Binanda Chandra Barua",
                "C. Chandra Kumar Agarwala",
                "D. Gunabhiram Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese poet is also known as \"Dhwoni Kobii\"",
            "answer": "B. Binanda Chandra Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Adani Group",
                "B. GMR Airports",
                "C. Reliance Group",
                "D. TATA Group"
            ],
            "question": "Which company wins the bid for lease to privatised Lokpriya Gopinath Bordoloi International Airport for next 50years",
            "answer": "A. Adani Group"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1996",
                "B. 1998",
                "C. 1999",
                "D. 2001"
            ],
            "question": "The Ministry of Development of North Eastern Region was established in the year",
            "answer": "D. 2001"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1992",
                "B. 1994",
                "C. 1996",
                "D. 1998"
            ],
            "question": "IIT Guwahati was established in the year",
            "answer": "B. 1994"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Siraj",
                "B. Swikarokti",
                "C. Mon-Prajapati",
                "D. Aarop"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the last film directed by Bhupen Hazarika",
            "answer": "A. Siraj"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Brazil",
                "B. Spain",
                "C. England",
                "D. Portugal"
            ],
            "question": "Which team wins the FIFA U-17 World Cup 2017 tournament",
            "answer": "C. England"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Three Star Club",
                "B. India East Bengal Club",
                "C. Mohammedan Sporting Club",
                "D. Oil India"
            ],
            "question": "Which team wins the Bordoloi Trophy Cup 2018",
            "answer": "C. Mohammedan Sporting Club"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Rita Devi",
                "B. Mamoni Raisom Goswami",
                "C. Nalinibala Devi",
                "D. Yamuneswari Khatoniar"
            ],
            "question": "The credit of first Assamese poetess plus first Assamese short story writer amongst women went to",
            "answer": "D. Yamuneswari Khatoniar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Majuli",
                "B. Bihpuria",
                "C. Mahmara",
                "D. Bokakhat"
            ],
            "question": "Which one below constituency of Assam Legislative Assembly reserved for Schedule Tribe",
            "answer": "A. Majuli"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ahom Kingdom",
                "B. Chutiya Kingdom",
                "C. Koch Kingdom",
                "D. Kachari Kingdom"
            ],
            "question": "The ruins of Bhismaknagar is belongs to which dynasty",
            "answer": "B. Chutiya Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Francis Jenkins",
                "B. David Scott",
                "C. Henry Hopkinson",
                "D. Thomas Campbell Robertson"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first British Commissioner of Assam",
            "answer": "B. David Scott"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sri Prakasa",
                "B. Jairamdas Daulatram",
                "C. Fazal Ali",
                "D. Muhammad Saleh Akbar Hydari"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Indian Governor of Assam",
            "answer": "D. Muhammad Saleh Akbar Hydari"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Birpal",
                "B. Ratnadhwajpal",
                "C. Mayuradhwajpal",
                "D. Satyanarayan"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the founder of the Chutiya Kingdom",
            "answer": "A. Birpal"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hiren Gohain",
                "B. Homen Borgohain",
                "C. Lou Majaw",
                "D. Yeshe Dorjee Thongshi"
            ],
            "question": "Who wins the 2017 Bhupen Hazarika Awards",
            "answer": "D. Yeshe Dorjee Thongshi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sadiya",
                "B. Vishwanath",
                "C. Ratnapur",
                "D. Swarnagiri"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was the first capital of the Chutiya Kingdom",
            "answer": "D. Swarnagiri"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1826",
                "B. 1828",
                "C. 1832",
                "D. 1834"
            ],
            "question": "In which year the Kachari Kingdom was annexed by British",
            "answer": "C. 1832"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1898",
                "B. 1902",
                "C. 1903",
                "D. 1905"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Assam Association was formed",
            "answer": "C. 1903"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ambikagiri Raichoudhury",
                "B. Jagannath Baruah",
                "C. Manik Chandra Baruah",
                "D. Raja Prabhat Chandra Baruah"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first President of Assam Association",
            "answer": "D. Raja Prabhat Chandra Baruah"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1879",
                "B. 1880",
                "C. 1881",
                "D. 1882"
            ],
            "question": "The first Railway line in Assam was established in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1881"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1895",
                "B. 1899",
                "C. 1901",
                "D. 1903"
            ],
            "question": "The Digboi Refinery was set up at Digboi by Assam Oil Company Ltd in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1901"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jorhat",
                "B. Golaghat",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Dhemaji"
            ],
            "question": "Environmentalist Robin Banerjee's Museum (Uncle Robin's Museum) is located in which district",
            "answer": "B. Golaghat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1979",
                "B. 1980",
                "C. 1981",
                "D. 1982"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Anwara Taimur becomes Assam's first and only female Chief Minister",
            "answer": "B. 1980"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Laysan duck",
                "B. Rufous-necked hornbill",
                "C. Pink-headed duck",
                "D. White-winged wood duck"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the state bird of Assam",
            "answer": "D. White-winged wood duck"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Environment/Conservation",
                "B. Children's Film",
                "C. National Integration",
                "D. Other Social Issues"
            ],
            "question": "In which category, the movie \"Dikchow Banat Palaax\" wins the Best Film award in the 2017 National Film Awards",
            "answer": "C. National Integration"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 7.45 km",
                "B. 8.25 km",
                "C. 9.15 km",
                "D. 10.10 km"
            ],
            "question": "The total length of the Dhola-Sadiya Bridge is",
            "answer": "C. 9.15 km"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhattadeva",
                "B. Sankardev",
                "C. Anirudhdev",
                "D. Madhavdev"
            ],
            "question": "Who is known as the father of Assamese prose literature",
            "answer": "A. Bhattadeva"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 3rd July",
                "B. 19th August",
                "C. 22nd September",
                "D. 29th October"
            ],
            "question": "Which day will be observed as Rhino Day in Assam",
            "answer": "C. 22nd September"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. S.K. Bhuyan",
                "B. Jogesh Chandra Dutta",
                "C. Tapan Roy Choudhury",
                "D. Dwarkanath Ganguly"
            ],
            "question": "The foundation of Nationalist Historiography in Assam was laid by",
            "answer": "A. S.K. Bhuyan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dhubri",
                "B. Goalpara",
                "C. Darrang",
                "D. Chirang"
            ],
            "question": "In which district the \"Sri Surya Pahar\" is located",
            "answer": "B. Goalpara"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 990",
                "B. 999",
                "C. 9999",
                "D. 99999"
            ],
            "question": "According to popular belief, how many Shiva Lingas were engraved in Surya Pahar by Vyasa in order to build up as asecond Kashi",
            "answer": "D. 99999"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kalika Puran",
                "B. Varuna Puran",
                "C. Vamana Puran",
                "D. Saura Puran"
            ],
            "question": "Which Puran was composed in the Assam",
            "answer": "A. Kalika Puran"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhanita Das",
                "B. Rupali Das",
                "C. Shikha Saikia",
                "D. Niyar Saikia"
            ],
            "question": "Which actress wins the National Film Award for Best Child Artist for the year 2017",
            "answer": "A. Bhanita Das"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jahnu Barua",
                "B. Moloya Goswami",
                "C. Rima Das",
                "D. Munin Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Who directed the movie \"Village Rockstars\" which wons the Best Feature Film ‘Swarna Kamal’ award at the 65thNational Film Awards",
            "answer": "C. Rima Das"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nilachal Peak",
                "B. Laike Peak",
                "C. Patkai Peak",
                "D. Kanduli Peak"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the highest peak in Assam",
            "answer": "B. Laike Peak"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Patkai Range",
                "B. Namcha Range",
                "C. Barail Range",
                "D. Bethartoli range"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the highest Mountain Ranges in Assam",
            "answer": "B. Namcha Range"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1",
                "B. 2",
                "C. 3",
                "D. 5"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of World Heritage Sites in Assam is",
            "answer": "B. 2"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Birpal",
                "B. Satyanarayan",
                "C. Vijayadhwajpal",
                "D. Ratnadhwajpal"
            ],
            "question": "Which Chutia king established Sadiya as the second capital of Chutia Kingdom",
            "answer": "D. Ratnadhwajpal"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Goalpara",
                "B. Nagaon",
                "C. Karbi Anglong",
                "D. Sibsagar"
            ],
            "question": "In which district of Assam, the majority settlements of Assamese Sikhs are found",
            "answer": "B. Nagaon"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ahom",
                "B. Koch",
                "C. Chutia",
                "D. Dimasa"
            ],
            "question": "Sati Sadhani was a queen of which dynasty",
            "answer": "C. Chutia"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nagaland",
                "B. Mizoram",
                "C. Tripura",
                "D. Arunachal Pradesh"
            ],
            "question": "Which State is not covered under the jurisdiction of Guwahati High Court",
            "answer": "C. Tripura"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sibsagar",
                "B. Jorhat",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Guwahati"
            ],
            "question": "The Lachit Borphukan's Maidam is located in",
            "answer": "B. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Muhammad bin Bakhtyar Khalji",
                "B. Murshid Quli Khan",
                "C. Hussamuddin Iwaz",
                "D. Nasiruddin Mahmud"
            ],
            "question": "The first Mohammedan invasion of Kamrup was lead by",
            "answer": "A. Muhammad bin Bakhtyar Khalji"
        }
    ]
}